Hello everyone, it's time for Enjoy Simple English
今年度からナビゲーターを務める森崎ウィンです
毎週木曜日は2019年度に放送した
Wisdom from the Westをお送りします
人生の知恵や教訓をさりげなく教えてくれる
イソップ偶話を集めました
今日はThe Fox and the Grapes
キツネとブドウです
これ僕も知らないのですごく楽しみです
さっそく聞いてみましょう
聞いてみましょう
うーん、このグレープは食べる準備ができる
私は食べたい
私はそれが美味しい
大きくてジューシーに見える
フォックスはグレープを長い間見ていました
思っていたのは、彼はそれを食べていたのです
でも、問題がありました
グレープは彼の頭の高さにありました
彼はそれを手に入れられませんでした
He thought for a moment.
Then, the fox had a good idea.
I know! I can jump!
Why didn't I think of that before?
I just have to jump, and then I can eat the grapes!
So the fox started jumping up and down to get the grapes.
But the fox could not touch them.
Finally,
The fox was so tired that he sat down to take a break.
He started to think again.
He didn't want to give up.
He wanted to eat the grapes so much.
Oh, I know. I will run and then jump.
If I run before I jump, then I can jump higher.
I am so smart. Okay, let's go.
Here I go!
The fox walked back down the road a little and got ready to run.
He thought,
I know I can do this! I want to eat the grapes!
One, two, three!
The fox ran up to the grapes and jumped as high as he could.
He flew through the air, but still he could not even touch the grapes.
I was so close. I almost got them. I know I can do it next time.
The fox tried again and again. But each time he could not reach them.
The fox sat down. He was very tired from jumping so many times.
I can't jump anymore. I have no more energy left in me.
疲れたフォークスは フォークスの上のグレープを見つけました
彼はそれを食べたくても でもそれがあまりにも高いのです
フォークスは 何を考えるか考え始めました
彼は考えた
私はクソだ!
このグレープは甘くないのです
酸っぱくないのです
見てください!
彼らはとても黒いのです
そしてとても大きいのです
うぅ!
i am a big fool i was jumping up and down for some sour grapes
the fox walked away from the grapevine with an angry look on his face
it is easy to hate what you cannot get
まさに人生の知恵教訓 勉強になりましたねこの話は
ちなみに英語でsour grapesという表現があるんですけれども
この偶話から生まれたそうなんですね
使い方としてはこれは例えば仕事の面接に落ちたとき
そんなときにthat is just sour grapesみたいな大した仕事じゃなかったよとか
その負け惜しみとして使うそうです
皆さん僕がさっき言ったのはあくまでも例文ですからね
I hope you will join me tomorrow. Have a great day.